Finding Aid for Ukrainians in the United States: Publications of Ukrainian-American organizations and institutions, 1924-1979
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ukrainians in the United States: Publications of Ukrainian-American organizations and institutions 1924-1979
[Ukrainian-American organizations and institutions]
1 linear foot
2009133 Aa 2
Ukrainian-American publications collected from various sources.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The materials were donated in part from John Panchuk (donor no. 5143 ) and came to the library in 1980.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The collection consists of publications, primarily from Ukrainian-American Michigan organizations and institutions.
Subjects:
Ukrainian Americans--Michigan
- Publications donated by John Panchuk
  - Federatsiï Amerïkans'kykh Ukraïntsiv V Mishigen. (Ukrainian-American Federation of Michigan) (Box 1)
    - Iubileinii Almanakh, 1939-1954 (Jubilee almanac) Detroit, 1954 (Box 1)
    - Zvit Z diial'nosty, 1939-1949 (Report on the activity) Detroit, 1949 (Box 1)
    - Statut. (Bylaws) Detroit, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Orhanizatsiia Oborony Ukraïny. (Defense of Ukraine)
    - Program I Statut. (Program and bylaws) New York, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Soviet-American Tractor Co-operative Association
    - Bylaws. Detroit, [19--] (Box 1)
  - Tovarystva Starshykh Vikam Ukraïntsiv V Mishigen. (Ukrainian Older Age Society in Michigan)
    - Status. (Bylaws) Detroit, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Ukrainian Art Exhibit, Wayne State University
    - Souvenir booklet. Detroit, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Ukraïns'ke Likars'ke Tovarystvo Pivnichonoï Ameryky. Michigans'kiï Viddil. (Ukrainian Medical Association of North America. Michigan Branch)
    - Likars'kiï Al'manakh. (Medical almanac) Detroit, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Ukraïns'kiï KongresoviÏ Komitet
    - Z Nahody Desiatylittia 1940-1950 New York, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Ukraïns'ko-Amerykans'koho Oseredka. (Ukrainian-American Center)
    - Statut. (Bylaws) Detroit, [19--]., 2 copies (Box 1)
  - Ukraïns'koïï Narodnoï Soiuz. Tovarystva im. M. Sichyns'koho, Viddil 146. (Ukrainian National Union. M Sichinsky Lodge 146)
    - Statut. (Bylaws) Hamtramck, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Ukraïns'koï Narodnoï Hromady V Nort Ditroït. (Ukrainian Community Home of North Detroit)
    - Statut. (Bylaws) Detroit, [1940] (Box 1)
  - Ukraïns'kyï Prosvitnyï Dim. (Ukrainian Educational Home Association)
    - Statut. (Bylaws) Detroit, 1923 (Box 1)
- Publications donated by the Ukrainian National Museum and Archives
  - Ukrainian National Museum and Archives
    - Report. [1964 ï], 1966, 1967, 1970, 1974, 1975, 1978, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Ukrainian Community Center, Warren, Mich
    - [Dedication booklet. December 16, 1978] (Box 1)
    - ----------------April 23, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Immaculate Conception Ukrainian Catholic Church, Hamtramck, Mich
    - Registered parish membership list 1955-58 (Box 1)
    - Sisterhood of the Immaculate Conception:-----------------[40th anniversary] 1959 (Box 1)
    - Golden anniversary booklet. 1969 (Box 1)
  - Immaculate Conception Ukrainian Catholic High School, Hamtramck, Mich.
    - The Basilea. 1977-1978 v.15, no.1, 3, 4, 5 (Box 1)
    - Icon: 1966, 1969, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Dedication booklet. 1952 (Box 1)
  - Ukrainian Medical Association of North America
    - ------------. Detroit, 1969 [Latin-Ukrainian medical dictionary] (Box 1)
    - Nomina anoatomica Ukrainica------------------. Detroit, 1971 (Box 1)
    - --------------. Chicago, 1975. [25th anniversary history] (Box 1)
    - Journal. no.66-91, 1972-1978 (some numbers missing) (Box 1)
  - Ukrainian Catholic Youth League
    - Sixth annual sports rally, Detroit, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Ukrainian Youth League of North America
    - Directory. 1954, 1956, 1957, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Mid-west rally, Detroit, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Ukrainian Youth Organization
    - ----------------. 1961-1976 no.31-65 (some numbers missing) (Box 1)
  - Ukrainian Bandurists Chorus
    - Programs, etc., 1 folder (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Miscellaneous programs of testimonial dinners, etc., 1 folder (Box 1)
    - Parfanowycz, Sophie. Fairylike Oakwood. Chicago, 1965. (Box 1)
      (in Ukrainian)
    - Taras Schevchenko memorial book. 1964 (Box 1)